Tan Yu Hui

+65 81269990 | yuhuitan22@gmail.com | Online Portfolio: https://yuhuitan.github.io/

PERSONAL PROFILE

A highly motivated Information Systems Technology and Design graduate with a strong interest in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Interaction Design, UI/UX, Usability and Ergonomics, as well as information systems. Sensitive to end-user and usability issues while also equipped with software engineering and system integration skills. Creative team-player with plenty working experiences in various industries. Highly adaptable in different working environments with great communication skills.

EDUCATION

Singapore University of Technology and Design

May 2016 - August 2019

- Bachelor of Engineering (Information Systems Technology and Design, Cybersecurity Specialization), Honors
- Graduated Cum Laude

WORK EXPERIENCES

Grab Holdings Inc, Cybersecurity Intern

May 2018 - August 2018

- Worked closely with GrabPay and Infosec Team to develop GrabPay Admiral, an application on the backend of GrabPay detecting fraudulent behaviours.
- At the end of the internship, produced a fully documented research paper on device fingerprinting, serving as the foundation of building fingerprinting systems like GrabPay Admiral in Grab's ecosystem.
- Formulated use cases for GrabPay Admiral, identified potential flaws and counter-produced relevant solutions for such issues.
- Researched heavily on mobile application frauds, identified parameters that can be exploited to profile fraudulent behaviours.
- Constructed relevant flowcharts as guidelines for onboarding new vendors into Grab's ecosystem

PolicyPal, Business Development Intern

May 2017 – August 2017

- Acquired new users for PolicyPal's phone application, over course of internship, increased user database by 30%.
- Represented company in career fairs at NUS and SMU, technology seminars hosted by e27 and Tech in Asia
- Showcased PolicyPal's products at an AIG mini conference.
- Represented company for a pitching competition to a group of investors in Lattice80 (largest Fintech hub in Singapore recognized by the Monetary Authority of Singapore).
- Utilized Google AdWords and Facebook Marketing to manage and analyse company's marketing spending, resulting in 40% growth of sales over 3 months.
- Liaised with companies such as WOOFR and Deliveroo for various partnerships.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

SMILE App Jan 2019 – May 2019

- Produced a fully functional wireframe of a dental app on Adobe XD, tackling key efficiency concepts of user interface design.
- Systematically explored trade-off between efficiency and learnability to frame the design problem and solution space.
- Conducted iterative, design/implementation process with series of brainstorming, literature reviews, sketching exercises, low/high-fidelity prototyping, usability testing with 32 participants, analysis and extraction of insights for design refinement.
- Managed to save up to 85% of time spend on appointment booking functions compared to traditional appointment booking methods in the market.

Flight Insurance DApp Project

Sept 2018 – Dec 2018

- Produced an end-user web application with purpose of allowing customers to purchase flight tickets with cryptocurrencies and allowing on-the-spot claiming for insurances.
- The decentralized application has smart contract designed by Solidity as its backbone.
- Front-end designs included the study of usability to ensure consistent, intuitive and easy-to-learn user-interface.

OTHER PROJECTS

CIMB NIAGA 3D CONQUEST HACKATHON

Dec 2018

- Worked in a team with two schoolmates to propose a solution to aid the unbanked population of Indonesia.
- 1 of 5 teams from Singapore that made it to the semi-finals.
- Over 24 hours, designed and prototyped the main wireframe of the mobile application using PhotoShop and Sketch.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Proficient in Python and Java. Intermediate HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Proficient in Adobe XD and Sketch.
- Fluent in English and Mandarin both spoken and written. Fluent in the Hokkien dialect.
- Outgoing personality with several experiences working in the service industry.